<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-01-30T22:33:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Beyond Borders</title><subtitle>Around the world</subtitle><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Puerto Rico | January 2024</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/america/puertorico/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Puerto Rico | January 2024" /><published>2024-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/america/puertorico</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/america/puertorico/"><![CDATA[<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">Puerto Rico</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">9 days (6-14 January 2024)</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">From the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/us">US</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Couple-trip</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">Currency: Dollar $</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/price">Price category</a>: 4</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Going to Puerto Rico started as a surprise gift idea for my partner’s 30th birthday. There are not that many destinations relatively close to Connecticut in the US that are warm and accessible in early January. A quick look at google <a href="https://www.google.com/travel/explore?tfs=CBwQAxoOagwIAhIIL20vMGYybmYaDnIMCAISCC9tLzBmMm5mQAFIAXACggELCP___________wGYAQE&amp;tfu=GgA&amp;tcfs=UgRgAXgB">flights</a> and I knew I wanted to fo somewhere in the Carribeans. I spoke with a friend from Costa Rica who told me that I would need more than a week to explore his country but recommended Cuba or Puerto Rico instead. Because my partner is a US citizen (and I’m on a visa), I realised quickly that Cuba would be a more difficult destination. Puerto Rico it would be!</p>

<p><br /></p>

<ol id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#puerto-rico-an-overview" id="markdown-toc-puerto-rico-an-overview">Puerto Rico. An Overview</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#history" id="markdown-toc-history">History</a></li>
      <li><a href="#how-safe-is-it" id="markdown-toc-how-safe-is-it">How Safe Is It?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#main-challenges" id="markdown-toc-main-challenges">Main challenges</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#my-trip" id="markdown-toc-my-trip">My trip</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#day-1---flying-into-san-juan-and-getting-to-utuado" id="markdown-toc-day-1---flying-into-san-juan-and-getting-to-utuado">Day 1 - Flying into San Juan and getting to Utuado</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-2---mountains-and-caves" id="markdown-toc-day-2---mountains-and-caves">Day 2 - Mountains and Caves</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-3---river-adventures-and-city-exploration" id="markdown-toc-day-3---river-adventures-and-city-exploration">Day 3 - River Adventures and City Exploration</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-4---vieques" id="markdown-toc-day-4---vieques">Day 4 - Vieques</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-5---beaches" id="markdown-toc-day-5---beaches">Day 5 - Beaches</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-6---el-yunque-forest" id="markdown-toc-day-6---el-yunque-forest">Day 6 - El Yunque Forest</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-7--" id="markdown-toc-day-7--">Day 7 -</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-8---old-san-juan" id="markdown-toc-day-8---old-san-juan">Day 8 - Old San Juan</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-9---santurce-and-departure" id="markdown-toc-day-9---santurce-and-departure">Day 9 - Santurce and Departure</a></li>
      <li><a href="#what-else" id="markdown-toc-what-else">What Else?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#my-budget" id="markdown-toc-my-budget">My Budget</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#my-tips-and-recommendations" id="markdown-toc-my-tips-and-recommendations">My Tips and Recommendations</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#how-to-move-around" id="markdown-toc-how-to-move-around">How to Move Around?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#how-long-should-you-stay" id="markdown-toc-how-long-should-you-stay">How Long Should You Stay?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#when-to-go" id="markdown-toc-when-to-go">When to Go?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#where-to-stay" id="markdown-toc-where-to-stay">Where to Stay?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#where-to-eat" id="markdown-toc-where-to-eat">Where to Eat?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#what-to-pack" id="markdown-toc-what-to-pack">What to Pack?</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><br /></p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/IMG-20240109-WA0005.jpg?raw=true" alt="Overview Puerto Rico" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="puerto-rico-an-overview">Puerto Rico. An Overview</h1>

<h2 id="history">History</h2>
<p>Puerto Rico is an archipelago located in the northeastern Caribbean, southeast of Florida. As a territory of the United States, Puerto Rico is an unincorporated territory with a unique political status that has implications for its history, politics, economy, and culture.</p>

<p>The indigenous Taíno people inhabited Puerto Rico before the arrival of Christopher Columbus in 1493. Spanish colonization began in the early 16th century, and the island became a strategic outpost in the Spanish Empire. Puerto Rico remained under Spanish rule for centuries. The island’s culture is deeply influenced by its Spanish heritage, seen in its language, religion, and architecture. Following the Spanish-American War in 1898, Puerto Rico was ceded to the United States under the Treaty of Paris. The Foraker Act of 1900 established a civilian government, and the Jones–Shafroth Act of 1917 granted U.S. citizenship to Puerto Ricans. In 1952, Puerto Rico adopted a Commonwealth status, establishing a local constitution. However, Puerto Rico remains an unincorporated territory, and its political status remains a complex and debated issue.</p>

<p>Puerto Rico has a locally elected government with its own constitution. The Governor of Puerto Rico leads the executive branch, and the Legislative Assembly comprises a Senate and House of Representatives. Although Puerto Ricans are U.S. citizens, they cannot vote in U.S. presidential elections. The island’s political status has been a subject of ongoing debate, with discussions about statehood, independence, or maintaining the current territorial status.</p>

<div style="float: left; margin-right: 20px;">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/IMG-20240109-WA0025.jpg?raw=true" alt="Your Image" width="450" />
</div>

<p>The economy of Puerto Rico has undergone various shifts. Historically, agriculture played a significant role, particularly in sugarcane and coffee production. In recent decades, the economy has diversified, with a focus on manufacturing, pharmaceuticals, services and tourism.
Puerto Rico has faced economic challenges, including a high debt burden and fiscal crises as well as natural disasters such as hurricane Maria in 2017.</p>

<p>Puerto Rican culture is a vibrant blend of Spanish, Taíno, African, and U.S. influences. The island is known for its music, dance, and festivals, including salsa, merengue, and bomba. Most people speak Spanish and Catholicism is the predominant religion. The arts, literature, and cuisine reflect the island’s rich cultural tapestry.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="how-safe-is-it">How Safe Is It?</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="general-observations">General Observations</h3>
<p>Given that Puerto Rico is a US territory, I was not sure what to expect: would the island be as unsafe as the rest of the mainland? However, until our last day, I felt quite safe. Locals were very welcoming and helpful and we had overall a great time. But on our last evening, our uber driver scared us by announcing that he had a gun in the car “for his and our safety”. Needless to say, that did not reassure us at all. Only Americans think that guns bring safey!</p>

<p>Other than that, we did not have to worry about other types of criminality. In Rio Abajo, we even made the mistake of not closing the door properly but nothing happened.</p>

<p>There was barely any language barrier: almost everyone speaks English and our memories of Spanish from highschool were enough to get around. The water is generally good but we decided to buy bottled water (big jars) to make sure we would be fine. We drank tap water in a few instances and had no issue at all.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="traveling-as-a-woman-and-a-lgbtq-person">Traveling as a Woman and a LGBTQ person</h3>
<p>In Puerto Rico, homosexuality is legal and San Juan even has a quite lively gay scene with many gay bars and clubs, such as <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/ni6HidNCkHvm86C3A">La Sombrilla Rosa</a> in Old San Juan.</p>

<p>It’s a touristy country and we felt safe as LGTBQ people. People are very friendly and helpful and we definitely liked that! This is definitely a gay-destination.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="main-challenges">Main challenges</h2>
<p>To be honest, Puerto Rico is a relatively easy destination, especially if you rent a car. If you do not, moving around (and out of San Juan) will probably be your biggest challenge.</p>

<p>Finding reasonably priced accomodations was probably my main challenge as Puerto Rico, a US territory, is really expensive. If you are on a budget, check airbnb and hostels rather than hotels. If you are willing (and able) to camp, this is also a solution to get cheaper accomodations. Accomodations in Vieques and Culebra are also a lot more expensive than the ones on the main island.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="my-trip">My trip</h1>
<h2 id="day-1---flying-into-san-juan-and-getting-to-utuado">Day 1 - Flying into San Juan and getting to Utuado</h2>

<div style="float: right; margin-left: 20px;">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240107_145851832.jpg?raw=true" alt="utuadoairbnb" width="450" />
</div>

<p>Our flight was slightly delayed and we arrived in San Juan in the late afternoon. After getting our luggage, we went searching for the shuttle service from our rental car company. We found it quickly and were on our way to the car rental place. The rental process went rather quickly (see below) and we were able to leave even before sundown. We decided to stop and get some groceries right next to Charlie’s, at <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/U3RKuBET2DcVm2F87">Supermercado Pueblo</a>, before getting on the road. The road to Utuado (about 1.5 hour) was quite good (despite a fair number a potholes). We stopped for dinner in Utuado at <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/GJsHqbUrxAKsBTH97">Tavos Pizza</a> before going to our airbnb. The last portion of the road was quite tricky but locals know how to avoid you. Drive slowly and you will be fine.</p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="pro-tips">Pro tips:</h3>
<p>If you arrive with an earlier flight, stop at the <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/kQbuj5HaX3bq5NDx5">Cueva del Indio</a> (see below) on the way to Utuado. We did it at the end of the trip and it was absolutely worth the visit! We wish we had done it in the beginning when we were in the region: that would have saved us a lot of time.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-2---mountains-and-caves">Day 2 - Mountains and Caves</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="primera-cascada-de-la-planta"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/ZutDEYUhouWbYKUc9">Primera Cascada de la Planta</a></h3>
<p>We had a slow morning and got on the road at 11am. We made the mistake to not call Camuy Caves and when we arrived shortly after 12pm, they told us that the next tour was at 2pm. With nearly 2 hours to kill, we had to think about another activity. We looked at the map and decided to drive to the Planta waterfall, nearly 30min from there. This was ABSOLUTELY worth it! This waterfall is easily accessible (3 min walk from the parking lot) and is GORGEOUS. There was barely anyone else and we were able to enjoy it until it was time to go back to Camuy.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240107_165503391.jpg?raw=true" alt="waterfallPlanta" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="camuy-caves"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/L7rTRpkXZbDezGzy8">Camuy caves</a></h3>
<p>Camuy Caves, also known as Parque Nacional de las Cavernas del Río Camuy, are a marvel of nature, formed over millions of years by the Camuy River. These expansive caves reveal an intricate underground world with impressive stalactite and stalagmite formations.</p>

<p>The visit is quite expensive (18$ per person) but worth it. This is a very interesting natural spot and the guides are very knowledgeable. You will walk downhill about 20+ minutes to the entrance of the cave. We had no issue with this tour, but some of the people with us struggled a lot. If you are in decent shape, you will be fine. Otherwise, they have golf carts that can help you go back up at the end of the tour.</p>

<p>You can book on their website <a href="">here</a>. The park is opened Wednesday through Sunday from 8:00 a.m. through 3:00 p.m. AST. For more information, please contact the Department of Natural Resources by calling (787) 898-3100 / (787) 999-2200 ext. 3474 or emailing cavernasdecamuy@drna.pr.gov.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240107_193407628.jpg?raw=true" alt="camuy" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="unplanned-expedition-in-the-jungle">Unplanned expedition in the jungle</h3>
<p>When we got back to our <a href="">airbnb accomodation</a>, we decided we wanted to go to the stream and small waterfalls that cross the property. We dropped everything, including water, food and lights and followed signs. We realised quickly that this little trip was much more challenging than expected when  we had to use a few ropes to go down. It turned out we took the longest and most diffcult trail on the property. When we finally got to the river, there was almost no sun light anymore and we gave up on exploring the area and finding the waterfalls. We decided to play safe and go back up as quickly as we possibly could.</p>

<video controls="" width="100%">
  <source src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/VID-20240107-WA0022.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
  
  <a href="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/VID-20240107-WA0022.mp4">WEBM</a>
  <a href="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/VID-20240107-WA0022.mp4">MP4</a>
</video>

<p>This little jungle trip was absolutely unplanned but we had so much fun!!!</p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="pro-tips-1">Pro tips:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Call Camuy before driving (or better: book a tour online) and go to the waterfall either before or after Camuy.</li>
  <li>Wear closed shoes (we recommend hiking shoes).</li>
  <li>If you are an early riser (and did not do it on day 1) you can also stop at the Cueva del Indio on the way.</li>
  <li>The Cueva Ventana, which we also wanted to visit is unfortunately permanently closed.</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-3---river-adventures-and-city-exploration">Day 3 - River Adventures and City Exploration</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="tanama-river-adventures"><a href="https://tanamariveradventures.com/">Tanama River Adventures</a></h3>
<p>Flowing through limestone canyons, the river offers opportunities for thrilling adventures. <a href="https://tanamariveradventures.com/">Tanama River Adventures</a> offers a number of tours including some with rappelling. We chose the <a href="https://tanamariveradventures.com/tours">Mukaro Cave Eco Tour</a> and it was amazing! The guides were very knowledgeable, kind and passionate about what they do.</p>

<p>The tour starts at 8.30am and we were back shortly after 12pm. The tour involved some hiking, visiting caves and learning about the bats that inhabit them, some easy rock climbing (and going up and down a small waterfall), walking and swimming in the river and some canyoning. We also got some free time to swim, jump, epxlore and take pictures, etc. at different spots.</p>

<p>This is definitely one of our best memories of this trip and we absolutely recommend it!</p>

<p><strong>Pro Tips:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>You need to be in decent physical condition as there is some hiking that is uphill, but it is not that bad. If you were able to do Camuy, you will have no issues here.</li>
  <li>Take water shoes or hiking boots.</li>
  <li>Wear athletic clothes (no denim shorts – or skirt! – like one woman who did the tour with us) that would get wet because you will be fully immersed in the water a couple of times.</li>
  <li>Bring your phone if you have a waterproof case/bag, otherwise, it’s risky. We only brought a gopro and left our phones at their office.</li>
  <li>Listen to the guides about wher you can and can’t go: some of the caves are not safe in all areas and you don’t want to take a risk.</li>
</ul>

<video controls="" width="100%">
  <source src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/raw/main/assets/img/puertorico/InShot_20240109_225149337.mp4" type="video/mp4" />

  <a href="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/raw/main/assets/img/puertorico/InShot_20240109_225149337.mp4">WEBM</a>
  <a href="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/raw/main/assets/img/puertorico/InShot_20240109_225149337.mp4">MP4</a>
</video>

<div class="row">
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/GOPR3670_ALTA3039056359705524600.JPG?raw=true" alt="cave" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/GOPR3605_ALTA3039056359705524600.JPG?raw=true" alt="Forest" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
</div>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="ponce"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/87tgazNk4g4rC2oh8">Ponce</a></h3>

<div style="float: left; margin-right: 20px;">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240108_214452424.jpg?raw=true" alt="ponce" width="450" />
</div>

<p>Ponce, known as the “Pearl of the South,” showcases a blend of colonial architecture and vibrant cultural heritage. Its historic town square, <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/wnY5Q5YJzL3NBHPN7">Plaza Las Delicias</a>, is a testament to the city’s development since its founding in the 17th century.</p>

<p>It’s a small town and we felt like there was not much to do. Most shops, restaurants and bars were closed and streets were empty but we might have gone at a wrong time (a Monday). The historic town square is (very) small but charming. We also spent some time at <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/HuKJQHdPjx8AjMAw8">La Guancha</a> and its beach which was a nice change from the mountains and jungle. If you like to collect shells, you’ll definitely find some cute ones there.</p>

<p>Overall, we do not particularly recommend staying in Ponce, but if you do, try to book a tour to <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/h4pXTBPfP2frTGkw7">Isla Caja de Muertos - Coffin Island</a>. It is apparently worth it.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="pro-tips-2">Pro tips:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Skip Ponce and drive direclty to Ceiba after the river adventure (and maybe stop to waterfalls or natural places on the road, such as <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/SNWXcJTZ4Qo7zCqL7">Charco Azul</a>).</li>
  <li>Book an accomodation in Ceiba and take an early morning ferry to Vieques instead of the 1pm one.</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-4---vieques">Day 4 - <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/YnWDzJpv4ZD3MoF7A">Vieques</a></h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="the-ferry-and-the-golf-cart">The Ferry and the Golf Cart</h3>
<p>There is a <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/edQc44FVyb8Y8v1f9">parking</a> close to the <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/WFrUFncHbLdBDzed6">Ferry terminal</a> in Ceiba qt q decent price (price per day) and they have shuttles to bring you to the terminal.</p>

<p>The ride in itself lasts about an hour, but it takes a bit more time as you need to board and disembark with MANY other people. We took the 1pm ferry and it was extremely crowded (and very turbulent). Booking for ferries open 1 month before the date you want and they only sell 20% of the tickets so try to book as early as you can. If you want to buy a ticket on the same day you want to travel, come at least 1 to 2 hours before the scheduled departure time. It takes time!</p>

<p>Once we arrived in Vieques, we went looking for the shuttle from <a href="https://www.utvrentalpr.com/">UTV rental</a>, the company I booked a golf cart with. They were easy to find BUT, they only drive the “main driver” to their office. You have to leave any other person at the Vieques terminal and come pick them up later with the golf cart. It is not written anywhere and I had not read any feedback anywhere, so imagine our suprise! Because we were already late on schedule (and only 2 people), we pretended we did not understand/hear what they said and both got in the cart (I know, it’s bad!). That saved us precious time. On the next morning though, we booked a taxi from their office to the <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/RtS42q1z1oud58VC6">Vieques ferry terminal</a> so we did not have to rely on their shuttle (or wake up insanely early to drop Sarah at the Terminal, drive back to their office and take the shuttle).</p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="media-luna-beach"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/FE9w4Dav5XLPV1Uo7">Media Luna Beach</a></h3>
<p>If you rent a car or a golf cart (we recommend it), drive to this beach which was recommended to us by Amanda at the Vieques Guesthouse. The road is quite bad and you’ll need some driving skills here (especially with a golf cart, a car should be totally fine), but it is absolutely worth it! And this is a fun drive.</p>

<p>Media Luna Beach is a hidden gem with golden sands and turquoise waters. And because the beach is difficult to reach, it is totally empty and absolutely stunning!</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240109_204411082.jpg?raw=true" alt="medialuna" /></p>
<div class="row">
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/IMG-20240109-WA0078.jpg?raw=true" alt="medialuna" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/IMG-20240109-WA0085.jpg?raw=true" alt="medialuna" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
</div>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="sun-bay-beach"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/BTQ2K1uf5AhsWXtM8">Sun Bay Beach</a></h3>

<p>Beautiful beach but many more people (more easily accessible). It’s also bigger. Definitely worth going if you don’t have a car/golf cart. You can also stop there on the way back from Media Luna.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/IMG-20240109-WA0031.jpg?raw=true" alt="Sun Bay" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="coconut-beach-el-cocal-beach">Coconut Beach (<a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/m3Nj6vcsUHikhFe18">El cocal beach</a>)</h3>
<p>This beach is right in front of the <a href="https://www.theviequesguesthouse.com/">Vieques Guesthouse</a>. In the parking lot, follow the small path in the forest and after a short walk (3min) you will arrive at this lovely, hidden beach. It is a beautiful place to watch the sunset and we had a great time there.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/IMG-20240109-WA0004.jpg?raw=true" alt="coconut" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="biobay-tour-in-mosquito-bay-at-night">Biobay tour in <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/jZqfZe9AemDDYejD7">Mosquito Bay</a> at night</h3>

<p>Mosquito Bay is known to be the brightest bioluminescent bay in the world, offering a surreal display of glowing waters. The bay is home to microorganisms called dinoflagellates, particularly the species Pyrodinium bahamense. These microscopic organisms emit a blue-green light when disturbed, creating a stunning display of bioluminescence in the water.</p>

<p>The unique combination of factors makes Mosquito Bay one of the brightest bioluminescent bays in the world:</p>
<ul>
  <li>The bay’s shallowness and its narrow entrance, limiting the renewal of water, which also makes it saltier.</li>
  <li>The presence of mangrove trees along its shores</li>
  <li>The lack of light pollution in the bay</li>
  <li>Lack of pollution (boats are forbidden, humans can’t swim in the water, etc.)</li>
</ul>

<p>The best time to witness the bioluminescence in Mosquito Bay is on moonless nights when the natural light pollution is minimal. Conservation efforts are in place to protect this delicate ecosystem, emphasizing the importance of sustainable tourism to preserve the beauty of Mosquito Bay for future generations.</p>

<p>We went on a tour with <a href="https://jakwatersports.com/">JAK Watersports</a> since they were recommended by our guesthouse. They provide clear-bottom canoes and limit groups to 16 people/8 canoes. Because I had already experience this phenomenon in the Fjords of Musandam in Oman, I thought I would not be surprised or amazed. But this bay is a lot more luminescent than what I experienced and the clear-bottom canoe provided a new really cool experience! Additionnally, the guides were very nice and knowledgeable and I learnt a lot! I definitely recommend their tour!</p>

<p>However, the logistics were not handled well, but this is partly my fault. I first emailed to get information. They answered, telling me there was availability the day I wanted at 7.45pm but I needed to call. I then called to book the tour. I gave all my information, including my email address, my phone number and my credit card details. They confirmed the tour for 2 was booked at 7.45. Fast forward to the day of the tour, I start to be anxious because I realise they never sent any confirmation by email or anything. We call and they confirm our booking (and actually send me an email this time), but at 6.30pm (but they don’t say it has changed). I had planned the entire day for a tour at 7.45 so I needed to adjust things and we ended up having less time to explore the island as I wanted and expected.</p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="pro-tips-3">Pro tips:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Ferry: book in advance and take an early morning ferry - these are less crowded. It will also give you more time on the island.</li>
  <li>Ferry : Arrive at least 30 minutes in advance.</li>
  <li>Book a golf cart and explore the island and its many beaches.</li>
  <li>Spend at least an entire day on the island. Take a morning ferry, stay overnight (for the biobay tour) and take a ferry the day after.</li>
  <li>Book the Biobay tour with JAK and pay cash to save 5$ per person. Additionally, when you call them to book, if you don’t receive a confirmation email, call them again or email them to avoid what happened to us.</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-5---beaches">Day 5 - Beaches</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="the-ferry-back-to-ceiba">The Ferry back to Ceiba</h3>
<p>We took the 10am Ferry and this was fairly uneventful. The ride was faster and there was less people. The only thing is that I wish we had spent more time in Vieques.</p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="natural-reserve-of-las-cabezas-de-san-juan"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/Qxc8R55hq53ydAE57">Natural Reserve of Las Cabezas de San Juan</a></h3>
<p>The plan was to spend the rest of the day in Fajardo and to go visit the <a href="https://reservaciones.paralanaturaleza.org/index.jsf">Natural Reserve of Las Cabezas de San Juan</a>. It is a coastal treasure with diverse ecosystems, including mangroves and coral reefs. Unfortunately for us, the guard at the entrance said it was closed because they are undergoing some conservation work at the moment. However, some comments on google indicate that it’s a reccurent thing but people can access the park from the beach: “One local couple explained that the gate always say no entry but we can access the paved road at various points and walk around the reserve.” I wish I had read the reviews that day…</p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="seven-seas-beach"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/MPhdB2mz6Dit5rxh6">Seven Seas Beach</a></h3>
<p>Because we thought we could not access the Reserve, we ended spending the afternoon at the Seven Seas Beach. There’s a large parking (5$ a day - only cards, no cash) and then you have access to the Seven Seas beach plus a number of others that are linked to it via some short hiking trails: <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/94vgauxfcQ6qtjtG8">Colora Beach</a> and <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/7W4v6pvFgLcxW34t8">Escondita Beach</a>. All are very nice and worth a visit. Although you can’t really swim at Colora beach because of the rocks and waves, walking there is worth it for the views! The path is not very long and doable with flip-flops or water shoes.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240110_192837473.jpg?raw=true" alt="sevenseas" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="pro-tips-4">Pro tips:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>The seven seas beach has a large parking (5$ a day).</li>
  <li>There are toilets and showers (free), which is definitely a plus.</li>
  <li>Explore the hiking paths to other beaches.</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-6---el-yunque-forest">Day 6 - <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/muFY85uB5e6mZXSi6">El Yunque Forest</a></h2>

<p>This day was supposed to be our diving/snorkeling day in Culebra. Unfortunately, because of the weather conditions, the trip was cancelled and we had to change the plan. This is my biggest deception of this trip - not diving and not seeing Culebra -  so if you have a chance, I would still recommend trying to spend a day diving/snorkeling on this island.</p>

<p>The company I booked with is <strong>Sea Ventures Pro Dive Center</strong> and, although we did not spend the day as planned, I would book all over again with them. The booking process was very easy and they are the only ones I could find that allow snorkelers, experienced divers and discovery divers on the same boat for the same trip. This was amazing because my partner does not dive but I didn’t want us to spend a day on two different boats doing different things in different places. They were also great handling communicationg about the weather and the problems (called, texted and emailed to make sure they reach me!) and proceeded with the refund instantly.</p>

<p>If you book with them and are lucky enough to have good weather, please let me know in the comments how the tour was!</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240111_172847091.jpg?raw=true" alt="maps" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="trail-vereda-bisley"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/MCrtBs8TMcxHbhaC8">Trail Vereda Bisley</a></h3>
<p>So, instead of diving and snorkeling, we spent the morning doing laundry before heading to el Yunque forest. El Yunque Forest, the only tropical rainforest in the US, is a UNESCO World Biosphere Reserve, known for its biodiversity and scenic trails.</p>

<p>I had planned to hike the <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/QuHGY3KaG6zDLBdb8">El Yunque Peak Trail</a> (8km) and the <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/3LoXB89D4in3JCHeA">La Coca trail</a> (6km) but, because
5 miles</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240111_185730472.jpg?raw=true" alt="Trail1" /></p>
<div class="row">
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240111_180421088.jpg?raw=true" alt="caution" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240111_191627519.jpg?raw=true" alt="trail" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
</div>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="angelito-trail-head"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/BJbaK5hQidHBgZYD7">Angelito Trail Head</a></h3>
<p>1.2km</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240111_210335260.jpg?raw=true" alt="trail2" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="pro-tips-5">Pro tips:</h3>
<p>Do not stop at the Visitors’ center. They make you pay at the entrance but it is not worth it if you’re like us and only want information about the trails. Instead, do this:</p>
<ul>
  <li>If you arrive early in the morning (between 8 and 9), you will most likely be able to enter the national park (for a fee) and do the El Yunque Peak trail and/or La Coca trail. They are indicated as challenging, but we noticed that most hiking trails’ difficulty is overestimated. If you exercise regularly at home and have hiking shoes, you’ll be fine.</li>
  <li>If you arrive later and can’t enter the park, do what we did as described above. The one we did is the other half of the Coca trail (but without the crowd and the fee to pay) and it was nice (albeit humid).</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-7--">Day 7 -</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="reserva-natural-cueva-del-indio">Reserva Natural Cueva del Indio</h3>
<p>Reserva Natural Cueva del Indio features ancient petroglyphs and stunning coastal views.</p>

<video controls="" width="100%">
  <source src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/raw/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240112_181130183.TS.mp4" type="video/mp4" />

  <a href="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/raw/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240112_181130183.TS.mp4">WEBM</a>
  <a href="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/raw/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240112_181130183.TS.mp4">MP4</a>
  video.
</video>

<div class="row">
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240112_181732154.jpg?raw=true" alt="cave" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240112_175528016.jpg?raw=tru" alt="Forest" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
</div>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="manantial-tortuguero-spring"><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/bQi5mm7XKopsdfZo7">Manantial Tortuguero Spring</a></h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240112_194028162.jpg?raw=true" alt="" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="santurce-and-la-placita-in-san-juan">Santurce and La Placita in San Juan</h3>
<p>Santurce is a vibrant urban neighborhood, pulsating with art, music, and nightlife in the well-known “La Placita”.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240112_235833279.MP.jpg?raw=true" alt="placita" /></p>

<h2 id="day-8---old-san-juan">Day 8 - Old San Juan</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="castillo-san-cristobal">Castillo San Cristobal</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240113_192555921.MP.jpg?raw=true" alt="sancristobal" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="fort-san-felipe-del-morro">Fort San Felipe del Morro</h3>

<div class="row">
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240113_202352086.MP.jpg?raw=true" alt="san Felipe" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240113_195229619.MP.jpg?raw=true" alt="san Felipe" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
</div>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="parque-de-los-gatos">Parque de Los Gatos</h3>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="old-san-juan">Old San Juan</h3>
<p>Old San Juan is a historic district with colorful colonial buildings, narrow cobblestone streets, and historic sites.</p>

<div class="row">
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240113_211024059.MP.jpg?raw=true" alt="oldsanjuan" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
  <div class="column">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240113_211848353.MP.jpg?raw=true" alt="oldsanjuan" style="width:100%" />
  </div>
</div>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="catedral-basilica-menor-de-san-juan-bautista-plaza-de-armas">Catedral Basilica Menor de San Juan Bautista, Plaza de Armas</h3>

<div style="float: left; margin-right: 20px;">
    <img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240113_211508747.MP.jpg?raw=true" alt="ponce" width="300" />
</div>

<p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="los-paraguas-de-la-fortaleza">Los Paraguas de la Fortaleza</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="paraguas" /></p>

<h2 id="day-9---santurce-and-departure">Day 9 - Santurce and Departure</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="brunch-at-abracadabra">Brunch at Abracadabra</h3>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="what-else">What Else?</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="in-san-juan">In San Juan</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Museum of Arts</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="outdoors-and-activities">Outdoors and activities</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Caves</li>
  <li>Waterfalls</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="islands">Islands</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Culebra</li>
  <li>Isla Caja de Muertos - Coffin Island</li>
  <li></li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="my-budget">My Budget</h2>
<p>Puerto Rico is an expensive island and our budget for this trip was quite important.
Our budget for this trip.</p>
<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Flight: Frontier airlines from Hartford to San Juan: <strong>395.92$</strong> for two people plus <strong>107$</strong> for one checked-in luggage (up to 40 pounds/18kg)</p>
  </li>
  <li>Accomodations
    <ul>
      <li>Utuado: <strong>136.86$</strong> for 2 nights</li>
      <li>Ponce: <strong>145.34$</strong> for 1 night</li>
      <li>Vieques: <strong>174.08$</strong> for 1 night</li>
      <li>Rio Abajo: <strong>175.62$</strong> for 2 nights</li>
      <li>San Juan: <strong>247.08$</strong> for 2 nights</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Activities:
    <ul>
      <li>Camuy Caves: <strong>18$ per person</strong> + 4$ for parking. <strong>40$</strong> in total.</li>
      <li><a href="https://tanamariveradventures.com/">Tanama River Adventures</a>: <strong>152.76$</strong> for 2 people for the Mukaro Cave Tour Experience.</li>
      <li>Biobay tour in Vieques with <a href="https://jakwatersports.com/">JAK Watersports</a>: <strong>55$ per person</strong> (because we paid cash). Add another 5$ per person if you pay with a credit card.</li>
      <li>Diving and snorkeling with <a href="https://divepuertorico.com/">Sea Ventures Pro Dive Center</a>: <strong>358.38$</strong> for 2 people, one diver (2 dives) and one snorkeler. This also included lunch and equipment rental. Because of the weather, we unfortunately had to cancel the dives and snorkeling that day.</li>
      <li>San Juan forts: <strong>10$ per person</strong>. The ticket includes entrance to both forts.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Food and drinks: <strong>xxx$</strong> for 2 people (only restaurants and cafes).
    <ul>
      <li>Groceries:</li>
      <li></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Transportation (taxis/ubers):
    <ul>
      <li>Car Rental with Charlie Rental Car for 7 days: <strong>302$</strong> includive of the toll option. We did not have to pay for insurance since we were able to use our US insurance. All non-US travelers have to purchase the mendatory insurance.</li>
      <li>Golf Cart with UTV for 1 day: <strong>xxx</strong></li>
      <li>Lyft from New Haven to Hartford for 2 people (round-trip): <strong>XXX$</strong></li>
      <li>Ubers in San Juan:</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Communication: 0$ since Puerto Rico is a US territory and we were able to use our sim cards.</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="pro-tips-6">Pro Tips</h3>
<ul>
  <li>In the US, unlike many other countries, taxes are not included in the price you see. They are added when you pay and you never really know how much you’re gonna end up paying.</li>
  <li>Similarly, because of their horrific conditions and laws for workers in the F&amp;B sector (the federal regular minimum wage in the U.S. is $7.25. However, employers are required to pay their tipped staff a “tipped minimum wage” of only $2.13 per hour), consumers bear responsibility for paying workers the remaining $5.12 per hour, about 71% of the minimum wage requirement. Therefore, tipping from 15 to 25% is customary for pretty much everything (buying a beer, a sandwich or dining at a restaurant, etc.). Workers will ask you every time if you want to tip and the card machine will usually suggest 18, 20, 22 and 25%. <strong>This adds quickly to the bill.</strong> You can usually add 35 to 40% to the announced price for food and beverage, and 10 to 20% for activities to get a rough idea of how much you’re gonna end up paying.</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="my-tips-and-recommendations">My Tips and Recommendations</h1>
<h2 id="how-to-move-around">How to Move Around?</h2>
<p>As usual, I would recommend renting a car unless you want to spend your time only in San Juan and/or Vieques/Culebra. Day-trips for San Juan are doable for some close locations and activities (Cueva del Indion Camuy Caves, etc.) but for any early activities, it becomes tricky. I love the independance provided by a car and it allows for last minutes changes of plans.</p>

<p>We HIGHLY recommend booking your car with <a href="https://www.charliecars.com/">Charlie Car Rental</a>. This is a locally owned company and they were amazing! This is truly the best rental car company I’ve ever rented with. They were so friendly, had a fast service and the car was great! The car was in a very good condition, and had android carplay and cruise control which made driving, having the gps and listening to music super easy.</p>

<p>What I really appreciated is the fact that they have great prices with no hidden fees: everything is mentioned on the website such as the price of the insurance you will need if you’re not from the US, what documents you need if you have a US insurance (call your company and make sure you’re covered in Puerto Rico and print all relevant documents), etc. They explain everything, unlike international companies which add fees once you are at the counter. We also took their toll offer, and it made our life SO MUCH easier! If you don’t take it, you have to take the right line at every toll gate, pay in cash (I think) and sometimes, the cashier is closed and I am not sure how things work in that case. Honestly, avoid the hassle, and take the Pre-paid toll option (or the Toll option if you won’t use the highway much).</p>

<p>The return process was also fast and easy. They gave me back my deposit (500) after a quick check of the car and we were done. I can’t recommend them enough!
They also have a shuttle service from and to the airport and are open 24/7.</p>

<p>To summarize:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Cheap and no hidden fees</li>
  <li>Shuttle to and from the airport</li>
  <li>Open 24/7</li>
  <li>Great cars and staff</li>
  <li>Take one of the toll options</li>
  <li>Check your insurance before arriving</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="how-long-should-you-stay">How Long Should You Stay?</h2>
<p>We stayed a long week and we wished we had a few more days. We would have loved to stay at least another day in Vieques, we did not have time to visit Culebra, and there is an astronomical number of waterfalls, beaches, caves and hiking trails I would have loved to see. Unless you want to stay in San Juan or in a resort, a week is probably the minimum and I would recommend up to two weeks to enjoy the entirety of the island(s) and their many activities.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="when-to-go">When to Go?</h2>
<p>January is the best season to travel to 
<br /></p>

<h2 id="where-to-stay">Where to Stay?</h2>
<p>We primarily used airbnb as hotels can be very expensive in Puerto Rico. Howevever, if you have the budget, Puerto Rico has a number of great hotels.
We booked a guest house in Vieques because of the great reviews and fair price for the island. We highly recommend each - but one - of the places where we stayed, for several different reasons:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Utuado: At Adam’s</li>
</ul>

<div class="airbnb-embed-frame" data-id="27434620" data-view="home" data-hide-price="true" style="width: 450px; height: 300px; margin: auto;"><a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/27434620?guests=1&amp;adults=1&amp;s=66&amp;source=embed_widget">View On Airbnb</a><a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/27434620?guests=1&amp;adults=1&amp;s=66&amp;source=embed_widget" rel="nofollow">Guesthouse in Utuado · ★4.77 · 1 bedroom · 5 beds · 1 shared bath</a><script async="" src="https://www.airbnb.com/embeddable/airbnb_jssdk"></script></div>

<ul>
  <li>Ponce: At Evelyn’s</li>
</ul>

<div class="airbnb-embed-frame" data-id="43782671" data-view="home" data-hide-price="true" style="width: 450px; height: 300px; margin: auto;"><a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/43782671?guests=1&amp;adults=1&amp;s=66&amp;source=embed_widget">View On Airbnb</a><a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/43782671?guests=1&amp;adults=1&amp;s=66&amp;source=embed_widget" rel="nofollow">Rental unit in Ponce · ★4.91 · Studio · 1 bed · 1 bath</a><script async="" src="https://www.airbnb.com/embeddable/airbnb_jssdk"></script></div>

<ul>
  <li>Vieques: <a href="https://www.theviequesguesthouse.com/">The Vieques Guesthouse</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Beautiful location with exceptionally helpful hosts (Amanda is a wealth of information - she helped us make the most of our short trip to the island!). The guesthouse is very clean and the rooms are super comfortable. It’s quite expensive but everything is on this island. This is honestly a good deal for the area.</p>

<p>Go up on the rooftop at night for a beautiful view of the stars. We loved our stay there and would definitely book again!</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240110_122120071.jpg?raw=true" alt="viequesgesthouse" /></p>

<ul>
  <li>San Juan: At Osvaldo’s</li>
</ul>

<div class="airbnb-embed-frame" data-id="10588304" data-view="home" data-hide-price="true" style="width: 450px; height: 300px; margin: auto;"><a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/10588304?guests=1&amp;adults=1&amp;s=66&amp;source=embed_widget">View On Airbnb</a><a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/10588304?guests=1&amp;adults=1&amp;s=66&amp;source=embed_widget" rel="nofollow">Guest suite in San Juan · ★4.74 · 1 bedroom · 1 bed · 1 bath</a><script async="" src="https://www.airbnb.com/embeddable/airbnb_jssdk"></script></div>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240112_215353149.MP.jpg?raw=true" alt="sanjuan" /></p>

<p>As for the one we do not particularly recommend, some of you might still find it interesting so we decided to post it here nonetheless:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rio Abajo;</li>
</ul>

<div class="airbnb-embed-frame" data-id="50116875" data-view="home" data-hide-price="true" style="width: 450px; height: 300px; margin: auto;"><a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/50116875?guests=1&amp;adults=1&amp;s=66&amp;source=embed_widget">View On Airbnb</a><a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/50116875?guests=1&amp;adults=1&amp;s=66&amp;source=embed_widget" rel="nofollow">Rental unit in Río Abajo · ★4.84 · 1 bedroom · 1 bed · 1 bath</a><script async="" src="https://www.airbnb.com/embeddable/airbnb_jssdk"></script></div>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="where-to-eat">Where to Eat?</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="in-san-juan-1">In San Juan</h3>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/AkHEDnqQg2dPgVCx8">Abracadabra</a> in Santurce for brunch</li>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/jXbqzPY5FnNMUyKs6">Café Comunión</a> in Santurce for breakfast</li>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/yW37QqW5wVG4Cj25A">Sea Señor La Placita</a>in Santurce (La Placita)</li>
  <li><a href="">Drunken Cookies</a> in Old San Juan</li>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/ix6u2DRzpoNRvkmV8">Bacaro</a> in Old San Juan for dinner (Italian)</li>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/ni6HidNCkHvm86C3A">LA SOMBRILLA ROSA</a> in Old San Juan for cheap drinks in a gay-friendly (and cute) bar.</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/puertorico/PXL_20240113_213303935.MP.jpg?raw=true" alt="drunkencookies" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="in-vieques">In Vieques</h3>
<p>We do not really have good recommendations in Vieques. We stayed only one night and our meal was not the greatest (<a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/k92osaaFdY5MzhxA6">Lazy Jacks</a>) because there was only one place serving food after the biobay tour. Try to get a later biobay tour and eat dinner before.</p>

<p>Our host recommended these places but we did not have the chance to try them:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/rRKGWPB4eAuK15QR9">Rancho Choli</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/Z3qL422UzpFkpupN8">Lizzy’s Lunchbox</a></li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="in-utuado">In Utuado</h3>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/Tox1tWQ1VdQYMdMy6">Utuado bakery</a>: very cheap and yummy sandwiches to pack for your daily excursions.</li>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/iBCTAZ6aCLWVXzEWA">Bier Garten</a> for lunch or an early dinner</li>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/X65xKzJj7zyu6cZD9">Tavo’s Pizza</a> for good and cheap pizzas, to dine-in or take-away.</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="in-ceiba-and-fajardo">In Ceiba and Fajardo</h3>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/SBBR1hJ55zMQiXMt7">Broadway Gastro Bar</a> for dinner in Ceiba. Good food (including Puerto Rican specialties) and drinks in a very cool atmosphere.</li>
  <li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/EiQBG3S3MJ7gugpm8">Rustica</a>: for italian food in Fajardo.</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="in-ponce">In Ponce</h3>
<p>We do not really have good recommendations in Ponce. We stayed only one night and our meal was not the greatest.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="what-to-pack">What to Pack?</h2>
<p>Everything!
We understimated how many clothes we would need and were lucky to be able to do some laundry in Rio Abajo, in the middle of our trip. Puerto Rico is a hot and humid island. This fact added to all the activities we did, we wore much more than one outfit a day (and you can’t reuse anything because you sweat!). You will need hiking equipment (both for hiking trails and if you want to do some river adventures), swimming equipment (canoe, snorkeling, diving, beach time, etc.), shorts and tee-shirts and dresses for city days and evenings and maybe a pair of pants for evenings and/or flights. Take more socks and underwear than the number of days you are staying, you will need them! And this advice also applies to shoes: hiking shoes, flip-flops, water shoes, city shoes, etc. I am usually an efficient packer and traveler and I really did not expect to use that many things.
You are now warned!</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<p><strong>Creation date: 19 January 2024</strong></p>

<p><strong>Last update: 19 January 2024</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><category term="america" /><category term="america" /><category term="city trip" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Hiking" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Puerto Rico 9 days (6-14 January 2024) From the US Couple-trip Currency: Dollar $ Price category: 4]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/puertorico.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/puertorico.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cyprus | October 2021</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/europe/cyprus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cyprus | October 2021" /><published>2023-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/europe/cyprus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/europe/cyprus/"><![CDATA[<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">Cyprus</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">8 days (15-22 October 2021)</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">From the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/uae">UAE</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Solo-trip</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">Currency: Euro € (1 € = 1.09 in 2024)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/price">Price category</a>: 3</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Cyprus was never a top country on my list of places I wanted to go to. However, when I needed a last-minute trip, relatively close to the UAE at the end of October 2021, my choice happened to be Cyprus. To this date, I have mixed feelings about this trip. Although I loved diving and hiking there, Cyprus remains a VERY tourist destination.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<ol id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#cyprus-an-overview" id="markdown-toc-cyprus-an-overview">Cyprus. An Overview</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#history" id="markdown-toc-history">History</a></li>
      <li><a href="#how-safe-is-it" id="markdown-toc-how-safe-is-it">How Safe Is It?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#main-challenges" id="markdown-toc-main-challenges">Main challenges</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#my-trip" id="markdown-toc-my-trip">My trip</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#day-1---paphos" id="markdown-toc-day-1---paphos">Day 1 - Paphos</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-2---paphos-and-diving" id="markdown-toc-day-2---paphos-and-diving">Day 2 - Paphos and Diving</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-3---diving-and-hiking" id="markdown-toc-day-3---diving-and-hiking">Day 3 - Diving and Hiking</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-4---hiking" id="markdown-toc-day-4---hiking">Day 4 - Hiking</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-5---monasteries-and-hiking" id="markdown-toc-day-5---monasteries-and-hiking">Day 5 - Monasteries and Hiking</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-6---cultural-sites" id="markdown-toc-day-6---cultural-sites">Day 6 - Cultural Sites</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-7---limassol-to-ayia-napa" id="markdown-toc-day-7---limassol-to-ayia-napa">Day 7 - Limassol to Ayia Napa</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-8---cap-greco-national-forest-park" id="markdown-toc-day-8---cap-greco-national-forest-park">Day 8 - Cap Greco National Forest Park</a></li>
      <li><a href="#what-else" id="markdown-toc-what-else">What Else?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#my-budget" id="markdown-toc-my-budget">My Budget</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#my-tips-and-recommendations" id="markdown-toc-my-tips-and-recommendations">My Tips and Recommendations</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#how-long-should-you-stay" id="markdown-toc-how-long-should-you-stay">How Long Should You Stay?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#when-to-go" id="markdown-toc-when-to-go">When to Go?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#where-to-stay" id="markdown-toc-where-to-stay">Where to Stay?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#where-to-eat" id="markdown-toc-where-to-eat">Where to Eat?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#how-to-move-around" id="markdown-toc-how-to-move-around">How to Move Around?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#what-to-pack" id="markdown-toc-what-to-pack">What to Pack?</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/Cyprus/IMG_20211021_174342.jpg?raw=true" alt="Ayia Napa" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="cyprus-an-overview">Cyprus. An Overview</h1>
<h2 id="history">History</h2>
<p>Cyprus is an island country located in the eastern Mediterranean Sea, situated at the crossroads of Europe, Asia, and Africa. It is the third-largest island in the Mediterranean and has a rich history, diverse culture, and stunning natural beauty.</p>

<p>It is an island nation with a complex history and a unique political status. Its rich history dates back to the Neolithic period, and it has been inhabited by various civilizations over the centuries, including Greeks, Romans, Byzantines, Venetians, Ottomans, and British who left their mark on this island.</p>

<p>It was conquered by the Ottoman empire in 1571, which resulted in three centuries of Turkish rule. In 1878, the British Empire took control of Cyprus in order to prevent Ottoman positions falling under control of Russia – and an agreement was reached which allowed the Ottoman Empire to retain ownership. In 1922, after the dissolution of the Ottoman Empire, the island remained under British control, up until 1960, when Cyprus gained independence from British colonial rule and became a republic. However, persistent intercommunal tensions between the Greek Cypriot majority and the Turkish Cypriot minority led to a Turkish invasion in 1974, resulting in the island’s division into two parts. The southern part, known as the Republic of Cyprus, is internationally recognized and a member of the European Union, while the northern part, the self-declared Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus, is recognized only by Turkey.</p>

<p>When people mention Cyprus, they usually talk about the southern part, the larger of the two parts. It covers approximately 63% of the island’s territory and includes cities such as Nicosia (the capital), Limassol, Larnaca, and Paphos. The self-declared state covers the remaining 37% of the island’s territory and is recognized only by Turkey and its major city is North Nicosia (Lefkoşa). The division between the two parts is marked by a United Nations-controlled buffer zone known as the “Green Line.”</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="how-safe-is-it">How Safe Is It?</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="general-observations">General Observations</h3>

<p>Cyprus is generally considered a safe destination for tourists and travelers. It has a relatively low crime rate compared to many other European countries and little risk to be mugged. However, as usual when traveling in most countries, be aware of your surroundings and ensure that your belongings are secure at all times.</p>

<p>Cyprus has a zero tolerance to drug possession and use, and being caught using or in possession will result in a heavy fine or prison term.</p>

<p>Crossing the Green Line is possible, but there are some important things to keep in mind:</p>
<ul>
  <li>There are designated official crossing points along the Green Line where individuals can cross between the two parts of the island. These are controlled by both Cypriot authorities and UN personnel.</li>
  <li>You will  need a valid passport or identity card to cross the Green Line. Visa requirements may also apply depending on your nationality and the purpose of your visit.</li>
  <li>The issue of the division of Cyprus is politically sensitive, and it’s essential to be respectful of local customs and sensitivities on both sides of the Green Line.</li>
  <li>Inside the buffer zone itself, access is typically restricted, and it is not a place for tourism. The buffer zone serves as a demilitarized area under the control of the United Nations.</li>
  <li>Be aware that there may be specific regulations and restrictions for crossing the Green Line. These can vary, so it’s advisable to check with the relevant authorities before your visit.</li>
</ul>

<p>Overall, since most countries do not recognise the northern part, their ability to provide consular assistance in this area may be limited. Be careful when traveling there.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/Cyprus/IMG_20211022_110821.jpg?raw=true" alt="Cap Greco" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="traveling-as-a-woman-and-a-lgbtq-person">Traveling as a Woman and a LGBTQ person</h3>

<p>I never felt unsafe traveling in Cyprus alone. People were usually nice and welcoming in the rural areas and nobody really paid any attention to me in the urban and touristy ones. I would say that Cyprus is a good location for any woman wanting to travel alone.</p>

<p>Regarding homosexuality, it has been legal in Cyprus since 2016 and civil partnerships can take place. There is a number of gay bar in the main cities (see below) and traveling with a partner is not a problem. However, away from the main cities LGBTQ+ people are not widely accepted. Nothing concerning or dangerous, but you might want to avoid too many public displays of affection.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="main-challenges">Main challenges</h2>
<p>For me, the main challenge of this trip was the transportation. I was moving almost everyday, and wanted to go to some rural areas in the mountains. I value my independance and I rented a car. However, Cyprus, as a former British colony, drives on the left. As a French person who has only lived in countries driving on the right, this was a MAJOR challenge. However, after a day or two, I got the hang of it, and it slowly became easier.</p>

<p>Other than that, I would say that there was no major issue, whether it was communication, safety, or health risk.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="my-trip">My trip</h1>
<h2 id="day-1---paphos">Day 1 - Paphos</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="paphos-fort-and-paphos-promenade">Paphos Fort and Paphos Promenade</h3>
<p>This 16th-century fort, originally built by the Ottomans and later reinforced by the British to protect the port. It is located at the western end of the city port and is a tangible reminder of Cyprus’s complex history under various rulers. The old stone walls, scarred by centuries of wear, spoke of the battles and maritime endeavors that once played out here.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/Cyprus/IMG_20211015_170753.jpg?raw=true" alt="Paphos Fort" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="archaeological-site-of-nea-paphos">Archaeological Site of Nea Paphos</h3>
<p>This site, originally founded in the late 4th century BC by King Nicocles, bore witness to the rich history of Hellenistic and Roman Cyprus. Among the well-preserved ruins, I marveled at the grand villas, intricate mosaics, and the Odeon theater that once hosted performances and gatherings. It was a journey into the architectural and artistic achievements of bygone eras.</p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="agia-kyriaki-chrysopolitissa">Agia Kyriaki Chrysopolitissa</h3>
<p>This old stone church, dating back to the 13th century, has witnessed centuries of devotion and worship.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-2---paphos-and-diving">Day 2 - Paphos and Diving</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="tombs-of-the-kings">Tombs of the Kings</h3>
<p>The Tombs of the Kings is a large necropolis lying about two kilometres north of Paphos harbour in Cyprus. These rock-carved burial chambers, dating back to the 4th century BC, were the final resting places of high-ranking officials and nobility. In 1980, it was designated a UNESCO World Heritage Site along with Paphos and Kouklia.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Tombs%20of%20the%20Kings/IMG_20211016_103337.jpg?raw=true" alt="Kings tombs" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="diving---sea-caves-with-into-the-blue-diving-center">Diving - Sea caves with “Into the Blue Diving Center”</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Sea%20caves/IMG_20211016_131659.jpg?raw=true" alt="Sea caves" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-3---diving-and-hiking">Day 3 - Diving and Hiking</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="diving---akamas-dive-sites-with-latchi-dive-center">Diving - Akamas Dive Sites with “Latchi Dive Center”</h3>
<ul>
  <li>St. George’s Island:</li>
</ul>

<p>This is the top dive spot on the Akamas Peninsula and among Cyprus’s finest. St. George’s Island’s west wall, the most popular part, starts at 10 meters and plunges to around 34 meters before sloping even deeper. There’s an abundant marine life, including Lionfish, Squirrelfish, Groupers, Amberjack, Peacock worms, and Nudibranch molluscs. Experienced divers can explore north along rock ledges, possibly spotting Moray eels. To end the dive, head back to the island and the dive boat, and at around 8 meters, you’ll discover a cave with remarkable stalactites. The east/south side of the island offers a shallow start with interesting rock formations. An array of fish species, from small Wrasse to Cornet/Trumpetfish, Squid, Cuttlefish, and Amberjacks, await.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Akamas%20Dive%20Sites/IMG_20211017_092909.jpg?raw=true" alt="St. George's Island" /></p>

<ul>
  <li>Amphitheatre Bay:</li>
</ul>

<p>Amphitheatre Bay dive site has a fascinating history, once serving as a Roman stone quarry and later used by the British Army as a firing range. Even today, if you look closely in the shallows, you may still discover remnants of old ammunition.</p>

<p>This site is suitable for divers of all experience levels. This is relatively shallow dive, starting at 7m and going up to 15m to 21m, but a beautiful one. Each bay offers a unique underwater landscape with diverse marine life. You might spot Moray eels, Octopus, small Rays, along with Damselfish, Flounder, Sea Stars, Nudibranch Molluscs, Sea Snails, and Sea Cucumbers.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Akamas%20Dive%20Sites/IMG_20211017_110058.jpg?raw=true" alt="Amphitheater bay" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="aphrodite-nature-trail">Aphrodite Nature Trail</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Baths of Aphrodite</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Aphrodite%20Nature%20Trail/IMG_20211017_161926.jpg?raw=true" alt="Aphrodite Nature Trail" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-4---hiking">Day 4 - Hiking</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="avakas-gorge-nature-trail">Avakas Gorge Nature Trail</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Avakas%20Gorge%20Nature%20Trail/IMG_20211018_110210.jpg?raw=true" alt="Avakas Gorge Nature Trail" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="pétra-tou-romioú">Pétra tou Romioú</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/P%C3%A9tra%20tou%20Romio%C3%BA/IMG_20211018_125843.jpg?raw=true" alt="Pétra tou Romioú" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="omodos">Omodos</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Omodos/IMG_20211018_144329.jpg?raw=true" alt="Omodos" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="caledonian-waterfall">Caledonian Waterfall</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Caledonian%20Waterfall/IMG_20211018_163400.jpg?raw=true" alt="Caledonian Waterfall" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-5---monasteries-and-hiking">Day 5 - Monasteries and Hiking</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="kykkos-monastery">Kykkos Monastery</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Kykkos/IMG_20211019_111439.jpg?raw=true" alt="Kykkos Monastery" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="xystarouda-hike">Xystarouda hike</h3>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="mount-olympus-and-artemis-hike">Mount Olympus and Artemis Hike</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Mount Olympus" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-6---cultural-sites">Day 6 - Cultural Sites</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="kourion-archaeological-site">Kourion Archaeological site</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/cyprus/Kourion/IMG_20211020_133630.jpg?raw=true" alt="Kourion" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="kolossi-castle">Kolossi Castle</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/Cyprus/IMG_20211020_150643.jpg?raw=true" alt="Kolossi Castle" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="limassol-castle">Limassol Castle</h3>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-7---limassol-to-ayia-napa">Day 7 - Limassol to Ayia Napa</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="getting-tattoed-in-limassol">Getting Tattoed in limassol</h3>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="monastery-of-ayia-napa">Monastery of Ayia Napa</h3>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="profitis-ilias">Profitis Ilias</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/Cyprus/IMG_20211021_174342.jpg?raw=true" alt="Ayia Napa" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-8---cap-greco-national-forest-park">Day 8 - Cap Greco National Forest Park</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="sea-caves">Sea Caves</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/Cyprus/IMG_20211022_121830.jpg?raw=true" alt="Sea caves" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="the-blue-lagoon">The Blue Lagoon</h3>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/Cyprus/IMG_20211022_110821.jpg?raw=true" alt="Blue Lagoon" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="what-else">What Else?</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="divings-sites">Divings sites</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Amphitheater</li>
  <li>Zenobia</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="hiking">Hiking</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Paphos Forest</li>
  <li>Millomeris Waterfalls Hike</li>
  <li>Kannoures – Agios Nikolaos Hike</li>
  <li>Enetika Gefyria (Venetian Bridges) Hike</li>
  <li>Atalanti Hike</li>
  <li>Agia Eirini – Limeria Hike</li>
  <li>Panagia tou Araka – Stavros tou Agiasmati Hike</li>
  <li>Psilo Dendro (Tall Tree) – Pouziaris Hike</li>
  <li>Kionia – Profitis Ilias Hike</li>
  <li>Xyliatos hike</li>
  <li>Selladi tou Karamanli – Kannavia Hike</li>
  <li>Madari – Selladi tou Karamanli hike</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="other-places">Other places</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Nicosia</li>
  <li>Larnaca</li>
  <li>Northern part of the country</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="other-cultural-and-archaeological-sites">Other Cultural and Archaeological sites</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Monastery of Saint John Lampadistes</li>
  <li>Machairas Monastery</li>
  <li>Stavrovouni Monastery</li>
  <li>Cyprus museum in Nicosia</li>
  <li>Wineries in the Troodos mountains</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="whats-in-the-northern-part">What’s in the Northern part?</h3>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="my-budget">My Budget</h2>
<p>My budget for this trip was relatively expensive, mainly because of the flight ticket and because I was traveling alone and therefore not sharing any cost (accomodations, car rental, etc.). I also dived which quickly adds up to the budget.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Flight: 651,44 €</li>
  <li>Accomodations:
    <ul>
      <li>Fitossin Hotel, 1 night: 77.40 €</li>
      <li>Peyia Pearl, 2 nights: 80 €</li>
      <li>Troodos Hotel, 1 night: 59.85 €</li>
      <li>Sofros Valley Hills Chalet, 1 night: 46.75 €</li>
      <li>Cornaro fine arts center, 1 night: 42.94 €</li>
      <li>Kokkinos Boutique Hotel, 1 night, breakfast included: 69.26 €</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Activities:
    <ul>
      <li>Diving:
        <ul>
          <li>Into the Blue diving center: 40 € per dive including transportation, equipment, snacks, water and photos/videos.</li>
          <li>Latchi Dive Center: 2 dives for 98 €</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>Cultural activities:
        <ul>
          <li>Kolossi Castle:</li>
          <li>Tombs of the Kings:</li>
          <li>Archaeological Site of Nea Paphos: €4,50</li>
          <li>Kykkos Monastery:</li>
          <li>Kourion:</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Food and drinks:</li>
  <li>Transportation:
    <ul>
      <li>Car rental: 315.00 €</li>
      <li>Gas:</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Communication:</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Total per person: $</strong></p>

<p>An important point: The Department of Antiquities issues <a href="http://www.culture.gov.cy/dmculture/da/da.nsf/DMLmuseums_en/DMLmuseums_en?OpenDocument">entrance tickets</a> that are valid for one day, three days or seven days to any museum and monument of the Department of Antiquities. The ticket can only be used once for each museum and ancient monument. These tickets cost:</p>
<ul>
  <li>1-Day special entry card: €8,50</li>
  <li>3-Day special entry card: €17,00</li>
  <li>7-Day special entry card: €25,00</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="my-tips-and-recommendations">My Tips and Recommendations</h1>
<h2 id="how-long-should-you-stay">How Long Should You Stay?</h2>
<p>This is a relatively small country. The rouads are usually in good condition, so if you can drive, you can move around quite easily. As usual, the amount of time you will need depends on what you plan on doing. I spent a good amount of time diving, which is why I did not have the time to go to Nicosia and some monasteries in the rural areas.</p>

<p>If you plan an itinerary like mine, a week is enough. However, if you plan on hking more or visiting other monasteries/cultural sites (or even the northern part of Cyprus), you might want to consider a slightly longer trip, ranging from 10 days up to 2 weeks.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="when-to-go">When to Go?</h2>
<p>XXX</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="where-to-stay">Where to Stay?</h2>
<p>Cyprus has a lot of options for all budgets. Because I was already spending a lot of money traveling on my own and diving, I chose housing options on the lower pricing range. You can obviously check some of the nicer options on Booking.com.</p>

<p>Here is a recap of the places where I stayed and their prices at the time:
    - Fitossin Hotel, 1 night: 77.40 €
    - Peyia Pearl, 2 nights: 80 €
    - Troodos Hotel, 1 night: 59.85 €
    - Sofros Valley Hills Chalet, 1 night: 46.75 €
    - Cornaro fine arts center, 1 night: 42.94 €
    - Kokkinos Boutique Hotel, 1 night, Breakfast included: 69.26 €</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="where-to-eat">Where to Eat?</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>XXX</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>XXX</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="how-to-move-around">How to Move Around?</h2>
<p>Cyprus is a small country with few big towns. If you are like me and want to travel to some of the rural areas, to hike in the mountains for example, I recommend renting a car. I value my independance and I love reaching empty places. I love to change my plan if I want or need to and I love to be able to stop somewhere unplanned if something catches my eye. Driving is, in my opinion, the way to go. And it is quite easy to park almost anywhere.</p>

<p>However, as I mentioned before, Cyprus is a former British colony, and therefore drives on the left. This was a MAJOR challenge for me, but not something insurmountable. After a day or two, I got the hang of it, and it slowly became easier. Don’t let that stopping you from enjoying the less touristy places of Cyprus.</p>

<p><strong>Another important point: rented tourist cars are clearly identifiable with red registration plates.</strong> You will be safer in a rented car than a local driving a car without marked plates. In general, local people keep their distance, drive more carefully around and are more forgiving with tourist cars. You can check <a href="https://www.thevivalavita.com/driving-in-cyprus-the-complete-guide/">this blog post</a> for the better idea of the driving situation in Cyprus.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="what-to-pack">What to Pack?</h2>

<p><br /></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CWQFuVKJ5bX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:16px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CWQFuVKJ5bX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"> <div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div></div></div><div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div> <div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><svg width="50px" height="50px" viewBox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"><g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></div><div style="padding-top: 8px;"> <div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;">View this post on Instagram</div></div><div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"><div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div></div><div style="margin-left: 8px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div></div><div style="margin-left: auto;"> <div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div></div></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div></div></a><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CWQFuVKJ5bX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Estelle Guéville (@estelle_gvl)</a></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p><br /></p>

<p><strong>Creation date: 20 September 2023</strong></p>

<p><strong>Last update: 20 September 2023</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><category term="europe" /><category term="Europe" /><category term="Solo-trip" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyprus 8 days (15-22 October 2021) From the UAE Solo-trip Currency: Euro € (1 € = 1.09 in 2024) Price category: 3]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/cyprus.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/cyprus.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Kazakhstan | April 2022</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/asia/kazakhstan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kazakhstan | April 2022" /><published>2023-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/asia/kazakhstan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/asia/kazakhstan/"><![CDATA[<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">Kazakhstan</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">8 days (2-9 April 2022)</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">From the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/uae">UAE</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Couple-trip</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">Currency: Kazakhstani Tenge ₸ (1₸ = 0.0022$ in 2024)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/price">Price category</a>: Between 1 and 2</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>In April 2022, I decided to go to Kazakhstan. If you have read my <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/asia/kyrgyzstan">Kyrgyzstan</a> post, you know that I was lucky to meet some Kazakhs who basically saved my life when I was hiking in Jeti Oguz in May 2021. I stayed in contact with them and I promised them that I would come and visit one day. That day came in April 2022. I knew my time in the UAE was limited and that I would not really get a chance to go to Kazakhstan after I moved to the US. This was the right time and I sent a text to my friends. In a few days, the trip was planned, the tickets booked, and here I was, flying once again to central Asia, but not alone this time.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<ol id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#kazakhstan-an-overview" id="markdown-toc-kazakhstan-an-overview">Kazakhstan. An Overview</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#history" id="markdown-toc-history">History</a></li>
      <li><a href="#how-safe-is-it" id="markdown-toc-how-safe-is-it">How Safe Is It?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#main-challenges" id="markdown-toc-main-challenges">Main challenges</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#my-trip" id="markdown-toc-my-trip">My trip</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#day-1---almaty" id="markdown-toc-day-1---almaty">Day 1 - Almaty</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-2---medeu---chimbulak" id="markdown-toc-day-2---medeu---chimbulak">Day 2 - Medeu - Chimbulak</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-3---canyons" id="markdown-toc-day-3---canyons">Day 3 - Canyons</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-4---kolsai-lakes" id="markdown-toc-day-4---kolsai-lakes">Day 4 - Kolsai Lakes</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-5---kaindy-lake-gorge-turgen-and-plateau-asy" id="markdown-toc-day-5---kaindy-lake-gorge-turgen-and-plateau-asy">Day 5 - Kaindy Lake, Gorge Turgen and Plateau Asy</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-6---waterfalls" id="markdown-toc-day-6---waterfalls">Day 6 - Waterfalls</a>        <ol>
          <li><a href="#butkowski-waterfall" id="markdown-toc-butkowski-waterfall">Butkowski Waterfall</a></li>
        </ol>
      </li>
      <li><a href="#day-7---almaty" id="markdown-toc-day-7---almaty">Day 7 - Almaty</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-8---departure-2pm" id="markdown-toc-day-8---departure-2pm">Day 8 - Departure (2pm)</a></li>
      <li><a href="#what-else" id="markdown-toc-what-else">What Else?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#my-budget" id="markdown-toc-my-budget">My Budget</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#my-tips-and-recommendations" id="markdown-toc-my-tips-and-recommendations">My Tips and Recommendations</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#how-to-move-around" id="markdown-toc-how-to-move-around">How to Move Around?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#how-long-should-you-stay" id="markdown-toc-how-long-should-you-stay">How Long Should You Stay?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#when-to-go" id="markdown-toc-when-to-go">When to Go?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#where-to-stay" id="markdown-toc-where-to-stay">Where to Stay?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#where-to-eat" id="markdown-toc-where-to-eat">Where to Eat?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#what-to-pack" id="markdown-toc-what-to-pack">What to Pack?</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><br /></p>

<p><img src="" alt="Overview Kazakhstan" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="kazakhstan-an-overview">Kazakhstan. An Overview</h1>

<h2 id="history">History</h2>
<p>Kazakhstan, once a member of the Soviet Union, occupies a strategic location at the crossroads of Central Asia and Eastern Europe. It stands as the largest landlocked country globally, sharing its borders with Russia to the north, China to the east, Kyrgyzstan, Uzbekistan, and Turkmenistan to the south, and being bordered by the Caspian Sea to the west. Kazakhstan’s geographical diversity encompasses expansive steppes, arid deserts, towering mountain ranges, and a shoreline along the Caspian Sea.</p>

<p>The history of Kazakhstan is a mosaic of diverse cultures and influences that span millennia. It has been inhabited since the Paleolithic era, hosting nomadic tribes such as the Turkic Khazars and experiencing the expansion of the Achaemenid Persian Empire in its southern regions. In the 13th century, it fell under the rule of the Mongol Empire led by Genghis Khan. The 15th century witnessed the establishment of the Kazakh Khanate, which later formed the core of modern Kazakhstan. By the 18th century, it became a part of the Russian Empire and later, a constituent republic of the Soviet Union. The path to independence commenced in 1991 with the dissolution of the USSR, culminating in Kazakhstan’s emergence as an independent nation.</p>

<p>Presently, Kazakhstan operates as a presidential republic characterized by a dominant-party system. Nursultan Nazarbayev served as the country’s inaugural president for nearly three decades until he stepped down in 2019. Kassym-Jomart Tokayev succeeded him and continues to serve as president as of the time of writing this blog post. Kazakhstan’s political landscape has been marked by efforts to balance relations with major powers like Russia and the West, while also holding memberships in international organizations such as the United Nations and the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS).</p>

<p>Economically and politically, Kazakhstan holds sway over Central Asia, contributing to 60 percent of the region’s GDP, primarily driven by its oil and gas industry and abundant mineral resources. Additionally, it boasts the highest Human Development Index ranking among its regional peers.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="how-safe-is-it">How Safe Is It?</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="general-observations">General Observations</h3>
<p>Kazakhstan is generally considered a safe country for tourists. It has a relatively low crime rate compared to many other countries, and violent crimes against tourists are rare.</p>

<p>However, some precautions should be taken, such as:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Be cautious about food and water hygiene. Drink bottled water as much as you can.</li>
  <li>Language Barrier: while many people in major cities, especially in the capital, Nur-Sultan (formerly Astana), and Almaty, speak English or Russian, you may encounter language barriers in more remote areas. It can be helpful to learn some basic phrases in Kazakh or Russian if you can (or hire a guide - see below).</li>
  <li>Altitude: If you plan to visit mountainous regions like Almaty or Shymbulak, be aware of the potential for altitude sickness and acclimatize accordingly.</li>
  <li>Border Areas: Some border areas, particularly near Kazakhstan’s borders with Russia, China, and some Central Asian countries, may have restricted access. Check the latest travel advisories and regulations if you plan to visit border regions.</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="traveling-as-a-woman-and-a-lgbtq-person">Traveling as a Woman and a LGBTQ person</h3>

<p>In Kazakhstan, Islam is the predominant religion, with Sunni Islam being the most widely practiced, coexisting harmoniously with other faiths. Religious tolerance is a cornerstone of Kazakh society, with freedom of religion guaranteed by the constitution. Russian Orthodox Christianity, Protestantism, Judaism, and other religious groups are also represented in the country. Kazakhstan is a secular state, but religion plays a significant role in its cultural fabric, observed through various religious holidays and traditions. The nation promotes interfaith dialogue and values its diverse religious heritage, which has left an indelible mark on its art, music, and architecture. Visitors are encouraged to respect local customs and appreciate the rich tapestry of religious diversity that defines Kazakhstan.</p>

<p>The situation for LGBTQ+ individuals in Kazakhstan is complex. Homosexuality is legal, but there are no specific anti-discrimination laws protecting LGBTQ+ rights. Social attitudes can be conservative in some areas, leading to discrimination and prejudice, while urban centers generally exhibit more tolerance. LGBTQ+ individuals may choose to keep their sexual orientation or gender identity private due to potential challenges. Pride events have faced opposition, and support organizations often operate discreetly. LGBTQ+ travelers should exercise caution, respect local customs and laws, and stay informed about the evolving situation, as acceptance and attitudes may vary across regions in Kazakhstan.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="main-challenges">Main challenges</h2>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="my-trip">My trip</h1>
<h2 id="day-1---almaty">Day 1 - Almaty</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="downtown-almaty">Downtown Almaty</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Zenkov Cathedral</li>
  <li>Walk in the city center</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="" alt="Zenkov Cathedral" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="thermal-sources">Thermal Sources</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Thermal Sources" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-2---medeu---chimbulak">Day 2 - Medeu - Chimbulak</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="medeu">Medeu</h3>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="skiing-in-chimbulak">Skiing in Chimbulak</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Chimbulak" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-3---canyons">Day 3 - Canyons</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="charyn-canyon-and-valley-of-castles">Charyn canyon and Valley of Castles</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Charyn" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="temirlik-canyon">Temirlik canyon</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Temirlik" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="uzunbulak-canyon">Uzunbulak canyon</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Uzunbulak" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-4---kolsai-lakes">Day 4 - Kolsai Lakes</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="lake-1">Lake 1</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Kolsai 1" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="lake-2">Lake 2</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Kolsai 2" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-5---kaindy-lake-gorge-turgen-and-plateau-asy">Day 5 - Kaindy Lake, Gorge Turgen and Plateau Asy</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="kaindy-lake">Kaindy Lake</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Kaindy lake" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="gorge-turgen">Gorge Turgen</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Gorge Turgen" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="medvegy-waterfall">Medvegy Waterfall</h3>

<p><img src="" alt="Medvegy Waterfall" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-6---waterfalls">Day 6 - Waterfalls</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="kairak-waterfall">Kairak Waterfall</h3>
<p>Kairak waterfall hike (16km)</p>

<p><img src="" alt="Kairak Waterfall" /></p>

<h3 id="butkowski-waterfall">Butkowski Waterfall</h3>
<p>Butkowski Waterfall (6km)</p>

<p><img src="" alt="Butkowski Waterfall" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-7---almaty">Day 7 - Almaty</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="xxx">XXX</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Central State Museum of Kazakhstan</li>
  <li>Kok Tobe</li>
  <li>Arba Winery</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="" alt="Almaty" /></p>

<h2 id="day-8---departure-2pm">Day 8 - Departure (2pm)</h2>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="what-else">What Else?</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="cities">Cities</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Astana</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="outdoor-activities">Outdoor activities</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Desert</li>
  <li>Boszhira</li>
</ul>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="cultural-and-archaeological-sites">Cultural and Archaeological sites</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Tamgaly</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="my-budget">My Budget</h2>
<p>My budget for this trip .</p>
<ul>
  <li>Flight:</li>
  <li>Tour guide all-inclusive: 482$ per person for 4 days. It includes;
    <ul>
      <li>Guide-driver</li>
      <li>Car</li>
      <li>Gas and related fees</li>
      <li>Accomodation</li>
      <li>Meals (breakfast, lunch, dinner)</li>
      <li>Entrance fees to National Parks</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Hotel:
    <ul>
      <li></li>
      <li></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Activities:
    <ul>
      <li>National museum of Qatar: QAR 25 (7$) per person.</li>
      <li>Sports museum: QAR 25 (7$) per person.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Food and drinks: QAR 609 (170$) for 2 people (only restaurants and cafes).</li>
  <li>Transportation (taxis/ubers): QAR 224.7 (60$) for 2 people.</li>
  <li>Communication: QAR 35 per sim card.</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="my-tips-and-recommendations">My Tips and Recommendations</h1>
<h2 id="how-to-move-around">How to Move Around?</h2>
<p>There’s one thing I must say: it is not the easiest thing in the world to move around on your own in Kazhakstan. Almaty is relatively well by public transit but as soon as you want to go out of the city, things are trickier.</p>

<p>The language barrier can also make things harder. Kazakhstan is a country where the population speaks mainly Russian beside the national language, Kazakh, a Turkic language close to Nogai, Kyrgyz and Karakalpak. Unfortunately, none of us spole any of these languages and the local population did not speak English, French or any other language we spoke. Communication was somewhat hard. To add to this, there are many police roadblocks, access to the mountains or the natural sites can sometimes be blocked for no reason and there is absolutely no way of knowing this before you are stopped by the police.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="how-long-should-you-stay">How Long Should You Stay?</h2>
<p>Kazakhstan is a huge country, the world’s ninth-largest country by land area and the world’s largest landlocked country. However, it has only 19 million people and one of the lowest population densitites. You won’t have the time to see all of the country. My advice would be to focus on a specific part of the country, like we did. The region of Almaty is usually one of the top choiches, along with Noursoultan (ex-Astana), the capital. From Almaty, you can travel around quite easily and visit many other places. I wouldn’t recommend going for less than a week. If you have time, ten days to two weeks is probably what I would recommend to get a good overview of the country.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="when-to-go">When to Go?</h2>
<p>XXX
<br /></p>

<h2 id="where-to-stay">Where to Stay?</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Almaty, Grand Hotel Tien Shan</li>
  <li>Almaty, Renion Park Hotel</li>
  <li>Saty Guesthouse</li>
  <li>Turgen gorge Guesthouse</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="where-to-eat">Where to Eat?</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Almaty, Dinner with Ilya and Julia (Victory’s pub)</li>
  <li>Pasta la Vista</li>
  <li>Diner in Cafe in Turgen</li>
  <li>“Bao Noodles Sushi Bar</li>
  <li>Pinta Bar”</li>
  <li>Mongol restaurant</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="what-to-pack">What to Pack?</h2>

<p><br /></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CfE2frALMDs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:16px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CfE2frALMDs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"> <div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div></div></div><div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div> <div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><svg width="50px" height="50px" viewBox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"><g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></div><div style="padding-top: 8px;"> <div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;">View this post on Instagram</div></div><div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"><div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div></div><div style="margin-left: 8px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div></div><div style="margin-left: auto;"> <div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div></div></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div></div></a><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CfE2frALMDs/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Estelle Guéville (@estelle_gvl)</a></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p><br /></p>

<p><strong>Creation date: 23 May 2023</strong></p>

<p><strong>Last update: 23 May 2023</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><category term="asia" /><category term="Asia" /><category term="City trip" /><category term="Nature" /><category term="Hiking" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kazakhstan 8 days (2-9 April 2022) From the UAE Couple-trip Currency: Kazakhstani Tenge ₸ (1₸ = 0.0022$ in 2024) Price category: Between 1 and 2]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/kazakhstan.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/kazakhstan.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Qatar | June 2022</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/middleeast/qatar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Qatar | June 2022" /><published>2023-09-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/middleeast/qatar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/middleeast/qatar/"><![CDATA[<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">Qatar</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">2 days (11-12 June 2022)</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">From the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/lived/middleeast/uae">UAE</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Trip with a friend</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">Currency</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Qatari Riyal (1 QAR = 0.27USD in 2024)</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/price">Price category</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Between 3 and 4</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>In June 2022, with more than 45°C (113°F), Doha has been my last trip from <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/abudhabi">Abu Dhabi</a>. After the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/middleeast/bahrain">Bahraini</a> surprise, I wanted to visit the Qatari capital and its museums before leaving the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/lived/middleeast/uae">UAE</a> for good to start a new life in the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/lived/america/usa">United States</a>. It has been a great discovery, full of amazingly sweet people, great food, culture and entertainment.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<ol id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#qatar-an-overview" id="markdown-toc-qatar-an-overview">Qatar. An Overview</a></li>
  <li><a href="#how-safe-is-it" id="markdown-toc-how-safe-is-it">How Safe Is It?</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#general-observations" id="markdown-toc-general-observations">General Observations</a></li>
      <li><a href="#traveling-as-a-woman-and-a-lgbtq-person" id="markdown-toc-traveling-as-a-woman-and-a-lgbtq-person">Traveling as a Woman and a LGBTQ person</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#main-challenges" id="markdown-toc-main-challenges">Main challenges</a></li>
  <li><a href="#my-trip" id="markdown-toc-my-trip">My trip</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#day-1---exploring-qatars-cultural-heart" id="markdown-toc-day-1---exploring-qatars-cultural-heart">Day 1 - Exploring Qatar’s Cultural Heart</a></li>
      <li><a href="#day-2---diving-into-qatars-history-and-sports" id="markdown-toc-day-2---diving-into-qatars-history-and-sports">Day 2 - Diving into Qatar’s History and Sports</a></li>
      <li><a href="#what-else" id="markdown-toc-what-else">What Else?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#my-budget" id="markdown-toc-my-budget">My Budget</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#my-tips-and-recommendations" id="markdown-toc-my-tips-and-recommendations">My Tips and Recommendations</a>    <ol>
      <li><a href="#how-long-should-you-stay" id="markdown-toc-how-long-should-you-stay">How Long Should You Stay?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#when-to-go" id="markdown-toc-when-to-go">When to Go?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#where-to-stay" id="markdown-toc-where-to-stay">Where to Stay?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#where-to-eat" id="markdown-toc-where-to-eat">Where to Eat?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#how-to-move-around" id="markdown-toc-how-to-move-around">How to Move Around?</a></li>
      <li><a href="#what-to-pack" id="markdown-toc-what-to-pack">What to Pack?</a></li>
    </ol>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><br /></p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar3.jpg?raw=true" alt="Overview Museum" /></p>

<h1 id="qatar-an-overview">Qatar. An Overview</h1>
<p>Qatar is a small country located in the Middle East, on the northeastern coast of the Arabian Peninsula. With a long history of foreign rule, by the Ottomans, and then as a British protectorate since 1916, Qatar declared its independence on September 3, 1971. It is now part of the GCC (Gulf Cooperation Council), an intergovernmental, political, and economic union established in May 1981, along with <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/middleeast/bahrain">Bahrain</a>, Kuwait, <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/middleeast/oman">Oman</a>, Saudi Arabia and the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/lived/middleeast/uae">United Arab Emirates</a>.</p>

<p>Qatar is, officially, a semi-constitutional and hereditary monarchy, ruled by the House of Thani since the late 19th century. The current Emir, the eighth, is Tamim bin Hamad Al Thani who has been ruling since 2013. A muslim country with only one border with the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, it counts 2.6 million inhabitants, among which only about 12% are Qataris (slightly more than 300 000 people). The rest of the population is made of expatriates from all over the world. It is also one of the wealthiest countries in the world with the fourth GDP (gross domestic product) per capita in 2020.</p>

<p>Qatar has recently been put under the light for hosting the 2022 FIFA World Cup, becoming the first Arab and Muslim-majority country to do so. The preparation of this event also highlighted a number of issues related to Human Rights as well as religious freedom and LGBTQ+ rights. Officially, as in the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/lived/middleeast/uae">United Arab Emirates</a>, Qatar uses the Sharia law, making apostasy and homosexuality crimes punishable by the death penalty while blasphemy is punishable by up to 7 years in prison. However, in practice, the country enforces a mixture of Sharia law and Civil law and, and no capital sentence has been recorded so far for the crimes above-mentioned.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="how-safe-is-it">How Safe Is It?</h1>
<h2 id="general-observations">General Observations</h2>

<p>After this rather scary introduction, you must wonder if it is safe for you to travel to Qatar. <strong>The answer is yes!</strong></p>

<p>Qatar, like most other countries in the GCC, is extremely safe. It is actually <strong>THE safest country</strong> in the world, just before the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/lived/middleeast/uae">United Arab Emirates</a> according to <a href="https://www.numbeo.com/cost-of-living/">Numbeo</a>. Other rankings usually put the country in the top 20 of the safest countries in the world. The crime rate is extremely low, and the government has taken steps to ensure the safety and security of visitors.</p>

<p>You do not need to worry about being robbed, you can leave your wallet on a table and go to the bathroom without fear of it being stolen, you can walk in the streets at night without fear of being mugged or attacked.</p>

<p>But is it safe for everyone?</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="traveling-as-a-woman-and-a-lgbtq-person">Traveling as a Woman and a LGBTQ person</h2>

<p>As I mentioned earlier, Qatar is extremely safe for men and women, but it is also a muslim country enforcing the sharia law. Officially, being gay in Qatar is illegal and punishable. In practice, things are a bit more blurry.</p>

<p>Countries in the Gulf have a strong sense of privacy and usually, what is private stays private. You should not publicly demonstrate affection, but this is also applicable to straight couples. Overall, everyone should be careful about their behaviour in public. Usually, it is even easier to travel as a gay couple because people will not expect you to be in a relationship. You will be considered to be friends most of the time.</p>

<p>I traveled with a female friend of mine. We shared the same room (separate beds) and did everything together. No one ever raised an eyebrow.</p>

<p>As a general advice when traveling in the Middle East, behave as friends and limit your demonstrations of affection - touching, kissing, etc. - in public and you won’t have any issue.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar/IMG3324.jpg?raw=true" alt="Sea" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="main-challenges">Main challenges</h1>
<p>For me, the main challenge of this trip was the weather. The heat made it hard to appreciate this country as I would have if I had traveled in the winter months. Other than that, everything was fairly easy: everyone speaks English, it is easy to move around, there is no safety issue whatsoever and no major health-risk (diseases, water/food problems, etc.). This is definitely an easy trip to organise, even for people who are not used to traveling.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="my-trip">My trip</h1>
<h2 id="day-1---exploring-qatars-cultural-heart">Day 1 - Exploring Qatar’s Cultural Heart</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="the-national-museum-of-qatar">The National Museum of Qatar</h3>
<p>We spent only a weekend in Qatar. As soon as we landed, we took a taxi and drove to the National Museum of Qatar, which is a must-see for anyone interested in the country’s history and culture. Designed by the French architect Jean Nouvel, the museum, which opened in 2019, is housed in a unique building that resembles the desert rose and showcases the history and culture of Qatar, from its ancient past to the present day.</p>

<p>We had lunch at the museum’s restaurant after the visit and this was one of the best meal I had in a while.</p>

<p>At that time, the museum of Islamic Art was closed so we headed to our hotel to check in, before heading to Katara Cultural Village.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar/nmq/IMG_20220611_101405.jpg?raw=true" alt="Overview Museum" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="katara-cultural-village">Katara Cultural Village</h3>
<p>Next, we headed to Katara Cultural Village, a cultural and artistic center that houses a number of galleries, theaters, and performance spaces. The village is also home to several restaurants, cafes, and shops, making it a great place to spend an afternoon exploring.</p>

<p>Don’t miss (you probably won’t be able to) the amphitheater in the middle of the village, also called the gem of the cultural village. The Katara Amphitheatre is a crafted balance between the classical Greek theatre concept and the everlasting Islamic features.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar/Katara/IMG_3212.jpg?raw=true" alt="Katara Amphitheatre" /></p>

<p>Have a look at the Golden Masjid (mosque), representing the Ottoman style and at the Masjid of Katara, which considered to be one of the most beautiful mosques in the country and was designed by globally-known Turkish mosque designer, Zainab Fadil Oglu.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar/Katara/IMG_3214.jpg?raw=true" alt="Golden Mosque" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="the-pearl">The Pearl</h3>
<p>Finally, we made our way to The Pearl, a man-made island that has been developed into a luxurious residential and shopping district. With its stunning waterfront, high-end shopping and dining, and beautiful marina, the Pearl is a must-see in the capital of Qatar.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar/Pearl/IMG_3266.jpg?raw=true" alt="Pearl" /></p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="qanat">Qanat</h3>
<p>The Qanat Quartier is a luxury residential development in The Pearl, Qatar, that takes its inspiration from traditional Arabic water villages, or “qanats.” It features a network of canals and waterways, surrounded by upscale retail and dining options, and is designed to be a family-friendly community. Traditionnally, a qanat is a system of underground channels that are used to transport water from an aquifer or a spring to surface for irrigation and domestic use. They are commonly found in the Middle East and North Africa and have been used for thousands of years. In Qatar, Qanats have played an important role in the development of agriculture and settlements, and have helped sustain life in a desert environment.</p>

<p>The Qanat Quartier reminded me of Europe, and particularly Italian towns. The architecture, the colours, they all makes you feel as if you are in Europe. However, the local touch can be found in the restaurants and cafes offering local and traditional cuisine. If you’re looking for a unique and upscale shopping and dining experience, the Qanat Quartier can be a great place to visit. The development offers a range of luxury shops, restaurants, cafes, and other amenities, set in a picturesque and peaceful environment that’s perfect for strolling. Whether you’re looking to buy souvenirs, sample some of the local cuisine, or simply spend a relaxing day in a beautiful setting, the Qanat Quartier is worth visiting.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar/qanat/IMG_3288.jpg?raw=true" alt="Qanat" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="day-2---diving-into-qatars-history-and-sports">Day 2 - Diving into Qatar’s History and Sports</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="souqs">Souqs</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Souq Waqif</li>
</ul>

<p>Our second day in Qatar started with a visit to Souq Waqif, an old-world market that has been a staple of Qatari life for centuries. Here, we had the chance to browse the stalls for traditional goods such as spices, textiles, and handcrafted items.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar/Waqif/IMG_3299.jpg?raw=true" alt="Souq waqif" /></p>

<ul>
  <li>Falcon Souq</li>
</ul>

<p>Next, I headed to the Falcon Souq, where we were able to see the magnificent birds of prey up close and learn about their importance in Qatari culture.</p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="qatar-olympic-and-sports-museum">Qatar Olympic and Sports Museum</h3>
<p>Finally, we ended our day with a visit to the Qatar Olympic and Sports Museum, which showcases the country’s rich sporting heritage and its commitment to promoting physical activity and wellness. The museum also features exhibits on the 2022 FIFA World Cup, which Qatar hosted, and highlights the country’s preparations for this global event.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar/qosp/IMG_3352.jpg?raw=true" alt="OlympicMuseum" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="what-else">What Else?</h2>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="museums">Museums</h3>
<ul>
  <li>The museum of Islamic Art.</li>
</ul>

<p>Aside from the sights I visited on Days 1 and 2, there were several other activities that I highly recommend during your trip to Qatar. The Museum of Islamic Art is a must-visit. It was unfortunately closed at the time I visited (June 2022) but the museum is now open and worth the visit. Its collection includes some of the most stunning examples of Islamic art from across the world.</p>

<h3 class="no_toc" id="outdoor-activities">Outdoor Activities</h3>
<ul>
  <li>The Desert</li>
</ul>

<p>If you are not from the Gulf, you should also do an excursion in the desert. It is a unique and otherworldly landscape that is well worth exploring. You have several options, a camel trek, dune bashing in a 4x4, or simply enjoying a sunset from the comfort of a bedouin tent. This is obviously a touristy activity but my recommendation would be to book a 4x4 dune bashing trip with an evening to rest, eat and stargaze (or night if you like to camp).</p>

<ul>
  <li>The Beach and Diving</li>
</ul>

<p>If you have time, also try to enjoy the beach, snorkeling and diving offers. It is the perfect escape from the hustle and bustle of city life. The Arabic Gulf offers clear blue waters and an abundance of marine life which make it a wonderful, not crowded place for relaxingin the sun and exploring marine waters.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="my-budget">My Budget</h2>
<p>My budget for this trip was relatively expensive for such a short trip, mostly because of the plane ticket which represents more than half of the total expenses.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Flight: 2 420,00 AED (660$) for 2 people.</li>
  <li>Hotel: QAR 453,60 (125$)for a room for 2.</li>
  <li>Activities:
    <ul>
      <li>National museum of Qatar: QAR 25 (7$) per person.</li>
      <li>Sports museum: QAR 25 (7$) per person.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Food and drinks: QAR 609 (170$) for 2 people (only restaurants and cafes).</li>
  <li>Transportation (taxis/ubers): QAR 224.7 (60$) for 2 people.</li>
  <li>Communication: QAR 35 per sim card.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Total per person: 560$</strong></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h1 id="my-tips-and-recommendations">My Tips and Recommendations</h1>
<h2 id="how-long-should-you-stay">How Long Should You Stay?</h2>
<p>It depends on your interests and travel goals, but I would recommend a 3-5 days visit. We only stayed 2 days because the museum of Islamic Art was closed and, since we lived in the UAE, we were not interested in the desert experience or the beach/snorkeling/diving one. An extended weekend allows for enough time to explore the top cultural and historical sites, experience the unique desert landscape, and enjoy some relaxation on the beaches or at luxury shopping destinations.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="when-to-go">When to Go?</h2>
<p>The best time to visit Qatar is from October to April, when the weather is the best. During that period, the temperatures range from 15-30°C (59-86°F), and the skies are usually clear and sunny, making it ideal for outdoor activities and sightseeing.</p>

<p>We visited Qatar in June and the temperatures were really high (up to 45°C/113°F) with a high humidity. It was definitely unpleasant and we did not enjoy the Souqs and other outdoor places as much as we would have in another context. We tried to stay inside as much as we could (museums were great for that!). If you are sensitive to heat, it may be best to avoid visiting during the summer months (May-September), when temperatures can reach up to 50°C (122°F) and humidity is at its highest.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="where-to-stay">Where to Stay?</h2>

<p>Qatar offers a wide variety of places where you can stay. Overall, because of the affordable prices and the culture, I recommend booking a hotel. <a href="">AirBnB</a> and other platforms are not as developped in the Gulf as they are in other countries in the World and, as mentioned earlier, countries in the GCC value their privacy.</p>

<p>Depending on your budget, you can book a double room in a 4-star hotel for as low as 50$. On the other hand, if you want to enjoy a 5-star experience at the <a href="">Banana Island Resort Doha by Anantara</a>, the prices can go up to 400$ a night.</p>

<p>We stayed at the <a href="">Al Najada Doha Hotel by Tivoli</a> and payed QAR 453,60 for 1 night (125$). As the time of writing this blogpost, the same room can be booked for 110$. As usual when I travel, I used the platform <a href="">Booking</a> to book my hotel. So far, I have never been disappointed in their service.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="where-to-eat">Where to Eat?</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Toro Toro:</li>
</ul>

<p>It is a popular Latin-American restaurant known for its creative and vibrant menu of authentic dishes, as well as its stylish and energetic atmosphere. The menu at Toro Toro is designed for sharing, and the restaurant encourages diners to sample a variety of dishes and flavors, including ceviche, tacos, and other small plates, as well as larger plates and grilled meats. In addition to the food, the restaurant also features a lively bar and lounge area, where you can enjoy cocktails, wine, and other beverages.</p>

<p>This is one of the best food I ever had in the region, especially compared to the UAE. Toro Toro is definitely worth checking out. I really enjoyed the menu, the atmosphere, and the energetic vibe. Whether you’re a fan of Latin American cuisine or simply looking for a fun and exciting dining experience, Toro Toro is a must-visit in Doha.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Jiwan</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="how-to-move-around">How to Move Around?</h2>
<p>There are several ways to move around in Qatar. We walked a lot and used very affordable taxis when moving from one neighbourhood to another. They are everywhere, easy to hail and are metered. No need to bargain!</p>

<p>Other options include:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Car Rental: Renting a car can be convenient if you want to explore the country at your own pace and see more than just Doha. The road network is well developed, most hotels have parking and valets, there are many parkings. There are several international car rental companies operating in the country. You can get a car at the airport or, if you prefer, your hotel in Doha can probably help you. However, traffic can be heavy in some areas, if you are not used to driving in the Gulf, it can be a bit tricky. This is not undoable but it’s important to familiarize yourself with the local driving laws and customs.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Public Transportation: Qatar’s public transportation system is still developing, but it is possible to get around using buses and the metro. The metro is clean, efficient, and affordable, and operates in the greater Doha area. Buses are also available and serve a wider area, but they can be crowded and less convenient.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>If you stay within Doha, taxis are, in my opinion, the most convenient way to move around.</p>

<p><img src="https://github.com/EstelleGvl/Around-the-World/blob/main/assets/img/qatar/Waqif/IMG_3311.jpg?raw=true" alt="Taxis" /></p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="what-to-pack">What to Pack?</h2>
<p>Qatar is a warm country but it’s also a quite traditional muslim country. Some places, such as some museums, do not accept people wearing shorts or short dresses. They will ask you to cover your legs (they provide a clothe to cover your legs if needed). But you can enjoy a pool or the beach in normal swimwear or bikini.</p>

<p>My recommendation would be to pack long pants/skirts and tee-shirts (no sleeveless) with either short or long sleeves. If you go in the summer, try to pack thin, natural and breathable materials such as linen. If you go in the winter, do not forget to bring at least one warm outfit: nghts can be cold, especially if you go in the desert. And for the women who plan to visit a mosque, do not forget a scarf to cover your head.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CgK5y_FIT3I/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:16px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CgK5y_FIT3I/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"> <div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div></div></div><div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div> <div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><svg width="50px" height="50px" viewBox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"><g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></div><div style="padding-top: 8px;"> <div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;">View this post on Instagram</div></div><div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"><div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div></div><div style="margin-left: 8px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div></div><div style="margin-left: auto;"> <div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div></div></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div></div></a><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CgK5y_FIT3I/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Estelle Guéville (@estelle_gvl)</a></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p><br /></p>

<p><strong>Creation date: 19 September 2023</strong></p>

<p><strong>Last update: 19 September 2023</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><category term="middleeast" /><category term="Middle East" /><category term="City trip" /><category term="Friends" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Qatar 2 days (11-12 June 2022) From the UAE Trip with a friend Currency Qatari Riyal (1 QAR = 0.27USD in 2024) Price category Between 3 and 4]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/qatar.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/qatar.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">France | 1992-2013 | 2014-2016</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lived/europe/france/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="France | 1992-2013 | 2014-2016" /><published>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lived/europe/france</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lived/europe/france/"><![CDATA[<base target="_blank" />

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">France</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">1992-2013 and 2014-2016</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">Currency: Euro € (1 € = 1.09 in 2024)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/price">Price category</a>: 3</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>The content of this page, as for any country where I lived, will be a bit different. It will focus on regions, activities and tips to travel like a local (transportation, accomodations, food, etc.). FInd the links to these specific pages below.</p>

<p>I was born and raised in France and it took me a while (moving to the US at 29) to realise how amazing my country is! Although I have not lived in France since 2016, I go back home at least once a year to see my family and my friends, which helps me staying updated about everything and makes me discover new regions and activities.</p>

<p>Let me know what content you would like to see here!</p>

<div class="lived" style="text-align: center;">
  <ul class="lived-posts">
          <li>
            <h3>
              <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/parispublictransportation">
                <div class="lived-thumbnail">
                    <img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/d8/Viaduc_Austerlitz_Paris_18.jpg" />
                </div>
                <div class="lived-title">
                  
                </div>
              </a>
            </h3>
          </li>
  </ul>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><category term="lived" /><category term="europe" /><category term="Europe" /><category term="lived" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/france.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/france.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Paris Public Transportation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/parispublictransportation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paris Public Transportation" /><published>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/parispublictransportation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/parispublictransportation/"><![CDATA[<base target="_blank" />]]></content><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/xxx.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/xxx.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">United Arab Emirates | 2016-2022</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lived/middleeast/uae/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="United Arab Emirates | 2016-2022" /><published>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lived/middleeast/uae</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lived/middleeast/uae/"><![CDATA[<p>XXX</p>]]></content><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><category term="lived" /><category term="middleeast" /><category term="Middle East" /><category term="lived" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[XXX]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uae.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/uae.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">United States of America | 2022 - now</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lived/america/usa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="United States of America | 2022 - now" /><published>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lived/america/usa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lived/america/usa/"><![CDATA[<base target="_blank" />

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">USA</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">August 2022 - Now</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">From the <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/uae">UAE</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Solo-trip</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">Currency: United Arab Emirates dirham - AED (0.27$ in 2024)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/price">Price category</a>: Between 3 and 4</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>The content of this page, as for any country where I lived, will be a bit different. It will focus on regions, activities and tips to travel like a local (transportation, accomodations, food, etc.). FInd the links to these specific pages below.</p>

<p>I moved in August 2022 to the US to pursue my PhD at Yale. I now live in New Haven, Connecticut, a small town located between New York and Boston. I will updated this content as I slowly discover more and more about this country.</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>

<div class="lived" style="text-align: center;">
  <ul class="lived-posts">
          <li>
            <h3>
              <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/ustransportation">
                <div class="lived-thumbnail">
                    <img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/d8/Viaduc_Austerlitz_Paris_18.jpg" />
                </div>
                <div class="lived-title">
                  
                </div>
              </a>
            </h3>
          </li>
  </ul>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><category term="lived" /><category term="america" /><category term="America" /><category term="lived" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/us.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/us.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Canada | 2013-2014</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lived/america/canada/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Canada | 2013-2014" /><published>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lived/america/canada</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lived/america/canada/"><![CDATA[<base target="_blank" />

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">Canada</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">8 months (August 2013 - May 2014)</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">From <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/france">France</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">Solo-trip</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">Currency: Canadian Dollar (0.74$ in 2024)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/price">Price category</a>: 3</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>The content of this page, as for any country where I lived, will be a bit different. It will focus on regions, activities and tips to travel like a local (transportation, accomodations, food, etc.). FInd the links to these specific pages below.</p>

<p>I lived in Canada in 2013-2014, more precisely in Quebec city while I pursuing my master’s degree in medieval history (exchange program). It was an amazing year and I hope to live in Canada again at some point of my life. In the meantime, because it is close(ish) to New Haven where I now live, I try to do regular trips to Montreal and other parts of the country.</p>

<p>This post will focus mostly on Quebec (and Ontario) as these are the only two provinces I have visited (or lived in) so far. I will keep everything updated as I discover more!</p>

<div class="lived" style="text-align: center;">
  <ul class="lived-posts">
          <li>
            <h3>
              <a href="https://estellegvl.github.io/Around-the-World/canadatransportation">
                <div class="lived-thumbnail">
                    <img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/d8/Viaduc_Austerlitz_Paris_18.jpg" />
                </div>
                <div class="lived-title">
                  
                </div>
              </a>
            </h3>
          </li>
  </ul>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Estelle Guéville</name></author><category term="lived" /><category term="america" /><category term="America" /><category term="lived" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/canada.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/canada.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>